Guide to the Cornell Cinema records, 1971-2000.
Cornell Cinema records
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Cornell Cinema records, 1971-2000.
37-7-4187
Cornell Cinema
11.3 cubic feet.; 6 mapcase folders.
Video, publications.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
The Cornell Cinema video collection includes U.S. and international art film and art video works and documentary, as well as video distribution catalogs. As director of Cornell Cinema from 1982-1994, Richard Herskowitz began a program of purchasing and lending film and video artworks on videocassette. Subsequent Cinema director Mary Fessenden continued this program as long as demand persisted, then donated the video collection to the Rose Goldsen Archive of New Media Art in 2014. The collection is an important part of the history of Cornell Cinema. The collection focuses on significant works of historical, international, independent art cinema and video art. It includes catalogs from two video art exhibitions and annual catalogs from video distributors of the 1980s and 1990s. It also has Cornell Cinema calendars and posters from 1971 to 1983.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
Cornell Cinema was founded in 1970 and has earned an international reputation as a university film series and also a media center dedicated to providing the Cornell community with experimental, avant-garde, independent, and mainstream media art and cinematic entertainment. With nearly 300 screenings each year, Cornell Cinema has been cited as one of the best campus film exhibition programs in the United States.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
The Cornell Cinema video collection includes U.S. and international art film and art video works and documentary, as well as video distribution catalogs. As director of Cornell Cinema from 1982-1994, Richard Herskowitz began a program of purchasing and lending film and video artworks on videocassette. Subsequent Cinema director Mary Fessenden continued this program as long as demand persisted, then donated the video collection to the Rose Goldsen Archive of New Media Art in 2014. The collection is an important part of the history of Cornell Cinema. The collection focuses on significant works of historical, international, independent art cinema and video art. It includes catalogs from two video art exhibitions and annual catalogs from video distributors of the 1980s and 1990s. It also has Cornell Cinema calendars and posters from 1971 to 1983.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell Cinema; Herskowitz, Richard; Cornell University. Motion picture theaters.
Subjects:
Motion picture theaters
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Due to the fragility and potential degradation of moving image and sound recordings, viewing and listening is limited to items that have been digitized. If an item is in another media format, you may request to have the item digitized for access. Information on ordering access copies may be found on our Reproductions and Permissions page.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Video Works
Boxes 1-11
Series II. Printed Materials
Box 12, Mapcase Folders 1-6
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Video Works
  - The Time Length: 60:00 Format: U-Matic, V-8054 (Box 1)
  - The Mask - Johan van der Keuken Length: 60:00 Format: U-Matic, V-8055 (Box 1)
  - Le Grand Gugnol (part 1 of 2) - Jean Marboeuf Length: 60:00 Format: U-Matic, 1987; V-8056 (Box 1)
  - Le Grand Gugnol (part 2 of 2) - Jean Marboeuf Length: 60:00 Format: U-Matic, 1987; V-8057 (Box 1)
  - Un Amour A Paris (part 1 of 2) - Merzak Allouache Length: 60:00 Format: U-Matic, 1987; V-8058 (Box 1)
  - Un Amour A Paris (part 2 of 2) - Merzak Allouache Length: 60:00 Format: U-Matic, 1987; V-8059 (Box 1)
  - Pekin-Central (part 1 of 2) - Camille De Casablanca Length: 60:00 Format: U-Matic, 1987; V-8060 (Box 1)
  - Pekin-Central (part 2 of 2) - Camille De Casablanca Length: 60:00 Format: U-Matic, 1987; V-8061 (Box 1)
  - Don't Start Me To Talking - Stephenson J. Palfi and John O'Neal Length: 42:37 Format: VHS, V-8062 (Box 1)
  - A Simple Case for Torture, OR How to Sleep at Night - Martha Rosler Length: 62:00 Format: VHS, 1983; V-8063 (Box 1)
  - KAPPA - Bruce and Norman Yonemoto Length: 28:00 Format: VHS, 1986; V-8064 (Box 1)
  - My Mother Married Wilbur Stump - Skip Sweeney Length: 28:00 Format: VHS, 1986; V-8065 (Box 1)
  - State of the Art: Art of the State? Length: 56:00 Format: VHS, 1991; V-8066 (Box 1)
  - It's Clean it just looks Dirty Length: 59:45 Format: VHS, 1986; V-8067 (Box 1)
  - Media Burn & the Cadillac Ranch Show - Ant Farm Format: VHS, 1986; V-8068 (Box 1)
  - Bill Viola: Selected Works Length: 54:21 Format: VHS, 1986; V-8069 (Box 1)
  - Bill Viola: Selected Works Length: 54:21 Format: VHS, 1986; V-8070 (Box 1)
  - I Do Not Know What it is I am Like - Bill Viola Length: 1:29:00 Format: VHS, 1986; V-8071 (Box 1)
  - Video Americana Length: 56:00 Format: VHS, 1986; V-8072 (Box 1)
  - SABDA - Daniel Reeves Length: 30:00 Format: U-Matic S, 1985; V-7983 (Box 2)
  - Love part I (recut) Format: U-Matic, 1985; V-7984 (Box 2)
  - Love part II (recut) Format: U-Matic, 1985; V-7985 (Box 2)
  - Joan Does Dynasty with Joan Braderman Length: 32:00 Format: U-Matic, 1985; V-7986 (Box 2)
    Hampshire College professor and stand-up theorist Joan Braderman takes on power and desire in TV's campiest series. "Joan Does Dynasty," a classic in feminist media deconstruction, is a hilarious look at the materialistic 80's in the context of the ordinary working person's life. Co-Director Manual Delanda. Screened at the Whitney Museum of American Art (2007) and New Museum of Contemporary Art in NYC (2008).
  - Fighting the Fundamentalist Fig Leaf Length: 29:00 Format: U-Matic, 1989; V-7987 (Box 2)
    The Mapplethorpe/Serrano controversies sparked a pressing debate on censorship of the arts. Artist David Avalos, Washington Project for the Arts' Philip Brookman, critic Coco Fusco, poet Allen Ginsberg and painter Leon Golub discuss the issues at stake. What is the conservative agenda behind arts censorship and what can we do to combat it?
  - Manhatta. Format: U-Matic, 1921; V-7988 (Box 2)
    Charles Sheeler and Paul Strand. Manhatta documents the look of early-20th-century Manhattan. With the city as subject, the film consists of 65 shots sequenced in a loose non-narrative structure, beginning with a ferry approaching Manhattan and ending with a sunset view from a skyscraper. The primary objective of the film is to explore the relationship between photography and film; camera movement is kept to a minimum, as is incidental motion within each shot. Each frame provides a view of the city that has been carefully arranged into abstract compositions.
  - My Mother Married Wilbur Stump - Skip Sweeney Length: 28:00 Format: U-Matic, 1986; V-7989 (Box 2)
  - Catherine Saalfield, Neil Lazarus and Kelly Anderson Read the Weekly Mail Length: 28:00 Format: U-Matic, 1987; V-7990 (Box 2)
    Analysis of an anti-apartheid South African newspaper with anti-censorship strategies and a non-racial social democratic vision.
  - Possibly In Michigan - Cecilia Condit Length: 12:00 Format: U-Matic, 1983; V-7991 (Box 2)
  - Party Safe! with Diana and Bambi - Ellen Spiro Length: 30:00 Format: U-Matic, 1992; V-7992 (Box 2)
  - TV Dante Cantos 1-4 (1 of 2) Length: 60:00 Format: U-Matic, 1989; V-7993 (Box 2)
  - TV Dante Cantos 5-8 (2 of 2) Length: 60:00 Format: U-Matic, 1989; V-7994 (Box 2)
  - URA ARU (the back side still exists) - Gary Hill Length: 28:00 Format: U-Matic, 1985-1986; V-7995 (Box 2)
  - Cornell 1969 Format: U-Matic, V-7996 (Box 2)
  - Torn Between Colors: Youth and the Media Length: 1:00:00 Format: U-matic, V-7997 (Box 2)
    Through Our Eyes Video and History Project - Satellite Academy High School Bronx.
  - Transformer/AIDS with Bob Kinney Length: 28:00 Format: U-matic, 1988; V-7998 (Box 2)
    At the end of his second term, Ronald Reagan finally addressed the issue of AIDS. Or did he? Certainly not without the homophobia, insensitivity and blatant lack of knowledge which plagues the whole of government around such issues. "Transformer AIDS" looks at the governmental response to AIDS at this crucial point in history, when activism forced the issue onto the public agenda. A sarcastically funny, yet poignant critique engineered spearheaded by critic Bob Kinney.
  - A Simple Case for Torture, OR How to Sleep at Night Length: 62:00 Format: U-Matic, 1983; V-7999 (Box 3)
    Martha Rosler identifies the totalitarian implications of an argument for torture, under certain circumstances, as it appears as a guest editorial in Newsweek magazine in 1982. Her critique is presented as a voiceover and a dizzying assemblage of radio and print media--articles on subjects ranging from human rights to unemployment and global economics. Implicating the U.S. government and American businesses for supporting regimes that systematically use torture, she indicts the American press for its role as an agent of disinformation through selective coverage and its use of language, and for implicitly legitimizing points of view that support torture.
  - Varda Burstyn Reads Playboy Length: 28:00 Format: U-Matic, V-8000 (Box 3)
  - Infermental #1: Public Images Length: 60:00 Format: U-Matic, V-8040 (Box 3)
  - Infermental #2: De-Colonized Media Length: 60:00 Format: U-Matic, V-8041 (Box 3)
  - Infermental #3: Sexuality or Gender Length: 60:00 Format: U-Matic, V-8042 (Box 3)
  - Infermental #4: Epidemics Length: 60:00 Format: U-Matic, V-8043 (Box 3)
  - Infermental #5: Image Dialects Length: 60:00 Format: U-Matic, V-8044 (Box 3)
  - The White Castle (1 of 2) - Johan van der Keuken Length: 60:00 Format: U-Matic, V-8045 (Box 3)
  - The White Castle (2 of 2) - Johan van der Keuken Length: 60:00 Format: U-Matic, V-8046 (Box 3)
  - The Way of the South (1 of 3) Length: 60:00 Format: U-Matic, V-8047 (Box 3)
  - The Way of the South (2 of 3) Length: 60:00 Format: U-Matic, V-8048 (Box 3)
  - The Way of the South (3 of 3) Length: 60:00 Format: U-Matic, V-8049 (Box 3)
  - The Flat Jungle (1 of 2) Length: 60:00 Format: U-Matic, V-8050 (Box 3)
  - The Flat Jungle (2 of 2) Length: 60:00 Format: U-Matic, V-8051 (Box 3)
  - Herman Slobbe/Blind Child 2 - Johan van der Keuken Length: 60:00 Format: U-Matic, V-8052 (Box 3)
  - # 1 Reading Lesson; The Door; Filmmakers Holiday Length: 60:00 Format: U-Matic, V-8053 (Box 3)
  - Animals in the Mass Media: Images of a Schizophrenic Society - John Sanbonmastu Format: U-Matic, V-8001 (Box 4)
  - Ynestra King Reads Seventeen Length: 28:00 Format: U-Matic, 1982; V-8002 (Box 4)
    Activist and Ecofeminist Ynestra King reads Seventeen magazine. Ynestra exposes how the publication's superficial and commercial based message to teen girls leaves them without the necessary tools for identity based empowerment and can ultimately isolate special needs and minority teen groups. Ms. King also outlines numerous non-commercial methods for improving this publication such as addressing much more common women's issues like community health resources, sexuality counseling and social awareness.
  - Donna Haraway Reads National Geographic on Primates Length: 28:00 Format: U-Matic, V-8003 (Box 4)
  - Murray Bookchin Reads Time Magazine Length: 28:00 Format: U-Matic, V-8004 (Box 4)
  - From Woodstock to Tiananmen Square Length: 28:00 Format: U-Matic, V-8005 (Box 4)
  - Herb Schiller Reads the New York Times "712 of Waste" Length: 28:00 Format: U-Matic, 1981; V-8006 (Box 4)
  - Just Say Yes! - Kathy High Length: 28:00 Format: U-matic, V-8007 (Box 4)
  - Born to be Sold: Martha Rosler Reads the Strange Case of Baby S/M Length: 28:00 Format: U-Matic, V-8008 (Box 4)
  - The Sluts and Goddesses Video Workshop - Maria Beatty, Annie Sprinkle Length: 52:00 Format: U-matic, 1992; V-8009 (Box 4)
  - Derek Jarman Short Films Length: 60:00 Format: U-Matic, V-8010 (Box 4)
  - Black Athena Length: 60:00 Format: U-Matic, V-8011 (Box 4)
  - Amazing Voyage of Gustave Flaubert and Raymond Roussel Length: 0:01:12 Format: U-Matic, 1986; V-8012 (Box 4)
  - KAPPA - Bruce and Norman Yonemoto Length: 28:00 Format: U-Matic, 1986; V-8013 (Box 4)
  - Buzz Box - David Daniels Length: 15:00 Format: U-Matic, 1986; V-8014 (Box 4)
  - Badung File: Burned to Death Length: 40:00 Format: U-matic, V-8015 (Box 4)
  - Godzilla Hey - Megan Roberts and Raymond Ghirardo Length: 02:20 Format: U-Matic S, 1988; V-8016 (Box 4)
  - Smothering Dreams - Dan Reeve Length: 23:00 Format: VHS, 1983; V-8073 (Box 5)
  - Ellis Island - Meredith Monk Length: 28:00 Format: VHS, 1982; V-8074 (Box 5)
  - Daniel Reeves Video Retrospective vol. 2 Length: 32:00 Format: VHS, 1989; V-8075 (Box 5)
  - Daniel Reeves Video Retrospective vol. 3 Length: 32:00 Format: VHS, 1989; V-8076 (Box 5)
  - Dog Star Man - Stan Brakhage Length: 1:15:00 Format: VHS, 1964; V-8077 (Box 5)
  - Continuum - Dominic Angerame Format: VHS, V-8078 (Box 5)
  - The Cinema of Transgression vol. 1 Length: 1:40:00 Format: VHS, 1986; V-8079 (Box 5)
  - Flesh Histories Length: 2:17:00 Format: VHS, 1992; V-8080 (Box 5)
  - Fuses - Carolee Schneemann Length: 23:00 Format: VHS, 1967; V-8081 (Box 5)
  - Invisible Adversaries - Valie Export Length: 1:52:00 Format: VHS, 1977, 1989; V-8082 (Box 5)
  - Dreamwood - James Broughton Length: 45:00 Format: VHS, 1972; V-8083 (Box 5)
  - Works by Jonathan Reiss Length: 1:07:00 Format: VHS, 1986-1988; V-8084 (Box 5)
  - Divine Horsemen: The Living Gods of Haiti - Maya Deren Format: VHS, 1986; V-8085 (Box 5)
  - Disorderly Concept Length: 29:00 Format: VHS, 1990; V-8086 (Box 5)
  - Video Against AIDS vol. 1 Length: 1:54:00 Format: VHS, 1989; V-8087 (Box 5)
  - Video Against AIDS vol. 2 Length: 1:55:00 Format: VHS, 1989; V-8088 (Box 5)
  - Video Against AIDS vol. 3 Length: 1:59:00 Format: VHS, 1989; V-8089 (Box 5)
  - Erotic Celebrations - James Broughton Length: 45:18 Format: VHS, 1988; V-8090 (Box 5)
  - L'Ange - Patrick Bokanowski Length: 1:10:00 Format: VHS, 1982; V-8091 (Box 5)
  - The Brig - Jona Mekas and Judith Malina Length: 55:00 Format: VHS, 1964; V-8092 (Box 5)
  - Blonde Cobra; Doctor's Dream - Ken Jacobs Length: 34:00; 23:00 Format: VHS, 1959-1963, 1978; V-8093 (Box 5)
  - Bruce Conner, Films: I - Bruce Conner Length: 24:00 Format: VHS, 1990; V-8094 (Box 5)
  - GBF Productions Compilation Format: VHS, V-8095 (Box 5)
  - Cathode Fuck: Video cutups by Christia N. Gorre Format: VHS, 1986; V-8096 (Box 5)
  - Mediums Well Done: Remaking Popular Culture Length: 56:00 Format: VHS, 1986; V-8097 (Box 5)
  - Paper Tiger invades Amerika starring "Ladies Against Women" Length: 2:00:00 Format: VHS, V-8098 (Box 5)
  - PPTV sampler Martha Rosler Reads Vogue Length: 2:00:00 Format: VHS, V-8099 (Box 5)
  - Two Moon July Length: 80:00 Format: VHS, 1987; V-8100 (Box 5)
  - Stations - Robert Wilson Length: 80:00 Format: VHS, 1982; V-8101 (Box 5)
  - Zbig Rybczynski: A Collection Length: 60:00 Format: VHS, 1985; V-8102 (Box 5)
  - The Paul Glabicki Animation Tape Length: 54:50 Format: VHS, 1992; V-8103 (Box 5)
  - RocketKitKongoKit - Craig Baldwin Length: 30:00 Format: VHS, 1986; V-8104 (Box 5)
  - George Kuchar Video (collection) Length: 90:00 Format: VHS, V-8105 (Box 5)
  - George Kuchar Videos vol. 2 (collection) Format: VHS, V-8106 (Box 5)
  - Mead Lake - Gary Kibbins Length: 28:00 Format: VHS, 1992; V-8107 (Box 5)
  - Three Films/Jerry Tartaglia Shorts Format: VHS, 1992?; V-8108 (Box 5)
  - Menschenfrauen - Valie Export Format: VHS, 1987; V-8109 (Box 5)
  - Journeys from Berlin/1971 - Yvonne Rainer Length: 2:05:00 Format: VHS, 1980; V-8110 (Box 5)
  - Angles of Incidence: Video Reflections of Multimedia Artworks Length: 1:54:15 Format: VHS, 1993; V-8111 (Box 5)
  - Animal Appetites - Michael Cho Length: 18:30 Format: VHS, 1991; V-8112 (Box 6)
  - Art Com Video 3: Max Almy Length: 40:00 Format: VHS, V-8113 (Box 6)
  - The Red Tapes - Vito Acconci Length: 2:22:00 Format: VHS, 1976; V-8114 (Box 6)
  - E.A.I. Video Art Format: VHS, V-8115 (Box 6)
  - Tribulation99: Alien Anomalies Under America - Craig Baldwin Length: 48:00 Format: VHS, 1991; V-8116 (Box 6)
  - Video Trans Americas - Juan Downey Format: VHS, 1989?; V-8117 (Box 6)
  - Information Withheld, Shifters - Juan Downey Format: VHS, 1984; V-8118 (Box 6)
  - Fireworks - Kenneth Anger Format: VHS, V-8119 (Box 6)
  - Inauguration of the Pleasure Dome - Kenneth Anger Format: VHS, V-8120 (Box 6)
  - Scorpio Rising - Kenneth Anger Format: VHS, V-8121 (Box 6)
  - Lucifer Rising - Kenneth Anger Format: VHS, V-8122 (Box 6)
  - John Cage - Peter Greenaway Length: 60:00 Format: VHS, 1985; V-8123 (Box 6)
  - Meredith Monk - Peter Greenaway Length: 60:00 Format: VHS, 1985; V-8124 (Box 6)
  - Philip Glass - Peter Greenaway Length: 60:00 Format: VHS, 1985; V-8125 (Box 6)
  - Robert Ashley - Peter Greenaway Length: 60:00 Format: VHS, 1985; V-8126 (Box 6)
  - Austrian Avant-Garde Cinema: 1954-1993 Length: 164, 1994; V-8127 (Box 6)
  - Maya Deren Experimental Films Length: 76:00 Format: VHS, 1986; V-8128 (Box 6)
  - The Brothers Quay Vol 1 Length: 35:06 Format: VHS, 1986; V-8129 (Box 6)
  - Shorter Works by Chantal Akerman Length: 89:00 Format: VHS, 1992; V-8130 (Box 6)
  - Shorter Works by Chantal Akerman Format: VHS, 1992; V-8131 (Box 6)
  - Three Films by Jerry Tartaglia Format: VHS, V-8132 (Box 6)
  - Carmen Miranda: Bananas is my Business - Helena Solberg Length: 90:00 Format: VHS, 1994; V-8133 (Box 6)
  - My Neighborhood - Mitchell Kriegman Length: 30:00 Format: VHS, 1982; V-8134 (Box 6)
  - Requiem - Alex Steyermark Length: 88:00 Format: VHS, 1989; V-8135 (Box 6)
  - National Arts Emergency Length: 29:00 Format: VHS, 1990; V-8136 (Box 6)
  - State of the Art: Art of the State? Length: 56:00 Format: VHS, 1991; V-8137 (Box 6)
  - A Personal Journey with Martin Scorcese Through American Movies (1 of 3) Format: VHS, 1995; V-8138 (Box 6)
  - A Personal Journey with Martin Scorcese Through American Movies (2 of 3) Format: VHS, 1995; V-8139 (Box 6)
  - A Personal Journey with Martin Scorcese Through American Movies (3 of 3) Format: VHS, 1995; V-8140 (Box 6)
  - A Personal Journey with Martin Scorcese Through American Movies (1 of 2) Format: VHS, 1996; V-8141 (Box 6)
  - A Personal Journey with Martin Scorcese Through American Movies (2 of 2) Format: VHS, 1996; V-8142 (Box 6)
  - The Scar Format: VHS, V-8143 (Box 6)
  - Tichborne Claimont Format: VHS, V-8144 (Box 6)
  - Robinson in Space Format: VHS, V-8145 (Box 6)
  - Mojo Format: VHS, V-8146 (Box 6)
  - Scandinavian Format: VHS, V-8147 (Box 6)
  - Scandinavian Format: VHS, V-8148 (Box 6)
  - France Format: VHS, V-8149 (Box 6)
  - France Length: 49:53 Format: VHS, 1996; V-8150 (Box 6)
  - Ireland Format: VHS, V-8158 (Box 7)
  - Great Britain Format: VHS, V-8159 (Box 7)
  - Latin America Format: VHS, V-8160 (Box 7)
  - Japan Format: VHS, V-8161 (Box 7)
  - Russia Format: VHS, 1996; V-8162 (Box 7)
  - Poland Format: VHS, V-8163 (Box 7)
  - New Zealand Format: VHS, V-8164 (Box 7)
  - Korea Format: VHS, V-8165 (Box 7)
  - Japan Format: VHS, 1995; V-8166 (Box 7)
  - Korea Format: VHS, V-8167 (Box 7)
  - Germany Format: VHS, V-8168 (Box 7)
  - Goodbye South, Goodbye - Hou Hsiao-Hsien Length: 2:00:00 Format: VHS, V-8169 (Box 7)
  - Puppet Master - Hou Hsiao-Hsien Format: VHS, 1999; V-8170 (Box 7)
  - Good Man, Good Women - Hou Hsiao-Hsien Length: 2:00:00 Format: VHS, V-8171 (Box 7)
  - Dust in the Wind - Hou Hsiao-Hsien Format: VHS, V-8172 (Box 7)
  - Flowers of Shanghai - Hou Hsiao-Hsien Length: 1:54:00 Format: VHS, V-8173 (Box 7)
  - A Time to Live A Time to Die - Hou Hsiao-Hsien Length: 2:21:00 Format: VHS, V-8174 (Box 7)
  - Booby Trapped for Revelation - Bradley Eros and Jeanne Liotta Format: VHS, 1990; V-8175 (Box 7)
  - Faces in a Famine - Robert Lieberman Format: VHS, V-8176 (Box 7)
  - Krzysztof Kieslowski: I'm So-So Length: 56:00 Format: VHS, 1995; V-8177 (Box 7)
  - Naked Making Lunch - Chris Rodley Format: VHS, 1992; V-8178 (Box 7)
  - Nothing As It Seems: The Films of Nicolas Roeg Format: VHS, V-8179 (Box 7)
  - Nagisha Oshima: The Man Who Left His Soul on Film Format: VHS, V-8180 (Box 7)
  - Paul and Menno: De Nooiger Length: 0:15:00 Format: VHS, V-8181 (Box 7)
  - Films of Pierre Herbert Format: VHS, V-8182 (Box 7)
  - Three Films by Michael Gitlin Length: 0:48:00 Format: VHS, V-8183 (Box 7)
  - Lost Book Found - Jem Cohen Length: 0:36:00 Format: VHS, 1996; V-8184 (Box 7)
  - Rules of the Road - Su Friedrich Length: 0:31:00 Format: VHS, 1993; V-8185 (Box 7)
  - The Genius - Joe Gibbons and Emily Breer Length: 1:26:00 Format: VHS, V-8186 (Box 7)
  - Rewe Installation - Juan Downey Format: VHS, V-8187 (Box 7)
  - The Time We Killed - Jennifer Reeves Length: 1:34:00 Format: VHS, 2004; V-8188 (Box 7)
  - Five 16mm Films -Jennifer Reeves, V-8189 (Box 7)
  - Jabbok; The Heavens; Razor Head; the Bath - Tom Chomont Format: VHS, V-8190 (Box 7)
  - Spectres of the Spectrum - Graig Baldwin Format: VHS, V-8191 (Box 7)
  - Documentaries on Neo-Realism Format: VHS, V-8192 (Box 7)
  - Imagined Communities: Cornell Cinema 1991 Format: VHS, 1991; V-8193 (Box 7)
  - Willard Straight Take-Over, Cornell 1969 - Patterson Diamant Format: VHS, V-8194 (Box 7)
  - New View 2/28/1990 (Media Services) Format: VHS, V-8195 (Box 7)
  - The Desert Bush - Sherry Millner and Ernest Larsen Length: 0:30:00 Format: VHS, 1991; V-8196 (Box 7)
  - The Art of Protective Coloration - Sherry Millner and Ernest Larsen Length: 0:16:00 Format: VHS, 1992; V-8197 (Box 7)
  - Eastern European Filmmakers Panel Discussion Part 1 Length: 1:00:00 Format: U-Matic, V-8198 (Box 8)
  - Eastern European Filmmakers Panel Discussion Part 2 Length: 1:00:00 Format: U-Matic, V-8199 (Box 8)
  - Interview with Fimmaker of "17" by Richard Herskowitz Length: 20:00 Format: U-Matic S, V-8200 (Box 8)
  - Tribute to Michael Baum (dub) Length: 20:00 Format: U-Matic S, V-8201 (Box 8)
  - Last Supper Length: 57:32 Format: Betacam SP, V-8202 (Box 8)
  - ?? [Jacob Hogdt]??? on case spine, only id Length: 60:00 Format: U-Matic, V-8203 (Box 8)
  - Farewell to Manzanar part II Length: 60:00 Format: U-Matic, V-8204 (Box 8)
  - ?? [1]?? Format: U-Matic S, V-8205 (Box 8)
  - Unequal Education: Failing our Children Length: 21:00 Format: VHS, V-8206 (Box 8)
  - What's Wrong with this Picture (feat. Jack Lemmon) Length: 22:00 Format: VHS, 1993; V-8207 (Box 8)
  - One Way Street - John Hughes Length: 59:00 Format: VHS, 1993; V-8208 (Box 8)
  - Milagro En Roma Length: 79:00 Format: VHS, 1990; V-8209 (Box 8)
  - Fabula de la Bella Palomera Format: VHS, 1990; V-8210 (Box 8)
  - La Ofrenda - Susana Munoz and Lourdes Portillo Length: 50:00 Format: VHS, 1996; V-8211 (Box 8)
  - Short Attention Span Film and Video Festival Part 1 Length: 60:00 Format: VHS, 1996; V-8212 (Box 8)
  - Short Attention Span Film and Video Festival Part 2 Length: 60:00 Format: VHS, V-8213 (Box 8)
  - Home Sweet Gone Length: 25:00 Format: VHS, V-8214 (Box 8)
  - Forbidden Love - Weismann and Fernie Format: VHS, 1992; V-8215 (Box 8)
  - U & I dot com - Branda Miller Length: 18:42 Format: VHS, 1999; V-8216 (Box 8)
  - Safer Sex Shorts - Gay Men's Health Crisis Length: 27:00 Format: VHS, 1989-1990; V-8217 (Box 8)
  - Home Sweet Home Format: VHS, V-8218 (Box 8)
  - The City Format: VHS, V-8219 (Box 8)
  - Flatbed - Craig Baldwin Format: VHS, V-8220 (Box 8)
  - Ghosts and Demons - Philip Mallory Jones Length: 03:00 Format: VHS, 1987; V-8221 (Box 8)
  - WSTM-WHEC-WBNG-WIXT: June 1985 Format: VHS, 1985; V-8222 (Box 8)
  - The Spell Length: 1:30:00 Format: VHS, V-8223 (Box 8)
  - Who's Who? Format: VHS, V-8224 (Box 8)
  - Big Pixel Format: VHS, V-8225 (Box 8)
  - Grown Ups - Mike Leigh Format: VHS, V-8226 (Box 8)
  - Break Moments - Mike Leigh Format: VHS, V-8227 (Box 8)
  - Abigail's Party - Mike Leigh Format: VHS, V-8228 (Box 8)
  - Regen; Philips Radio; Niieuwe Gronden - Joris Ivens Format: VHS, V-8229 (Box 9)
  - Song of the Rivers - Joris Ivens Format: VHS, V-8230 (Box 9)